<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Grant&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grant&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 19:08:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://grantdickins.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Power Automate - Intune Cert Connector Health</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2023/12/16/Power-Automate-Intune-Cert-Connector-Health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2023/12/16/Power-Automate-Intune-Cert-Connector-Health/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll start off by saying I don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand what I&amp;rsquo;ve done here. This whole process stemmed from having to do some icky dev stuff in order to keep my Intune Dev tenant active.
I still find it unbelievably moronic that MS don&amp;rsquo;t provide a tenant for testing Intune without forcing us to do dev stuff to keep it active - I&amp;rsquo;m on my 4th tenant now and it&amp;rsquo;s a PITA setting everything up again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mystery of Required Reboots during Autopilot</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2023/03/30/mystery-of-required-reboots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:59:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2023/03/30/mystery-of-required-reboots/</guid>
      <description>Businesses pay tens of thousands of $currency for Microsoft Partner consultants to come in, &amp;ldquo;modernise&amp;rdquo; their EUC estate, and leave behind a plethora of bugs and issues that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist because said partners are supposed to be &amp;ldquo;industry experts&amp;rdquo;.
Completely unrelated, an issue I was working on at a client was with their Autopilot setup left behind from an MS partner that was causing a forced reboot mid-ESP. Shortly after entering company credentials, there would be a 10 minute reboot warning and no way to cancel - other than Shift+F10 and running shutdown -a which a normal end user wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intune Audit Logs</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2023/03/27/intune-audit-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 22:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2023/03/27/intune-audit-logs/</guid>
      <description>Find who created/deleted/modified a configuration profile
Not that we operate in a blame culture and I&amp;rsquo;m sure you don&amp;rsquo;t either, but sometimes you need to know who created, deleted, or modified a configuration profile because sometimes people need hit with a jabby stick!
Intune Audit Logs In Intune, we have some lovely Audit Logs under Tenant administration. Permissions To access and review Audit log data, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to be in one of the following roles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Installer Resources</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/15/other-installer-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 12:50:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/15/other-installer-resources/</guid>
      <description>Setup Technologies MSI See post: MSI Installer
MSI Authoring Tools Wix Toolet - Free - Hard to learn
Master Packager - Freemium
MSI Installer Tool (advancedinstaller.com) - Freemium
InstallShield See post: InstallShield Setups
Wise Wise Setup files are a discontinued technology, but are still fairly prevalent.
Setup switches are very simple.
ITNinja.com has an article on them here Article: Wise Setup.exe Switches (itninja.com)
Usual silent install parameter: setup.exe /S
Nullsoft NSIS Website: NSIS Wiki (sourceforge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InstallShield</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/14/installshield/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 22:35:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/14/installshield/</guid>
      <description>InstallShield Setups When running InstallShield setups, they usually have this icon: And the setup dialogue looks like this:
These setup files are often a Setup.exe. There are two types; InstallScript and InstallScript MSI.
InstallScript MSI - Setup.exe has InstallScript inside that drives the install of an MSI. NOTE - Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled into thinking you can just run the MSI - The Setup.exe will likely also run some other pre-requisite checks, custom actions, and/or post installation actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSI Windows Installer</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/14/msi-windows-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 21:42:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/14/msi-windows-installer/</guid>
      <description>MSI Files These are generally easy as 3.14. If the vendor has adhered to MS standards then it should just be a case of running the MSI with:
MSIEXEC /i setup.msi /qn
Parameter Meaning MSIEXEC is the install engine. /i means install. /qn means quiet, no dialogue. Try: run &amp;ldquo;msiexec&amp;rdquo; in cmd to see the options.
Things get a little more complicated when vendors start adding custom dialogues to the setup process, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Silent Parameters</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/14/finding-silent-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 21:10:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2022/10/14/finding-silent-parameters/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what the setup file&amp;rsquo;s silent install switches are, there are a few ways to find out.
(Also, you will want the silent/unattended uninstall commands too.)
RT*M Check the vendor documentation. Sometimes they&amp;rsquo;ll provide the info needed to silently install their product. Even better if they actually provide step by step instructions on how to install via Config Manager! (But don&amp;rsquo;t get your hopes up&amp;hellip;)
Just Bing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 14:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? My name is Grant Dickins. I am a bit of a geek. I used to be more of a geek, but family life has calmed me down (read: Can&amp;rsquo;t afford to buy geeky stuff anymore.) I&amp;rsquo;m a career geek now. I spend my working time (and a little more) learning, researching, implementing, and managing Windows technology - usually in the form of Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager and associated toolsets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Permissions</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2021/07/03/github-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2021/07/03/github-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Error When trying to git clone or git push I would get the following error:
git@github.com: Permission denied (public key). fatal: Could not read from remote repository.
Please make sure you have the correct access rights and the repository exists.
To fix this, you need github to trust the machine.
On your machine, run:
ssh-keygen Keep it simple by just pressing Enter, Enter, Enter.
grunt@debian:~/dotfiles$ ssh-keygenGenerating public/private rsa key pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CfgMgr Distribution Priority</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2020/11/27/cfgmgr-distribution-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2020/11/27/cfgmgr-distribution-priority/</guid>
      <description>Quick one.
We have some remote DPs that are rate limited during business hours, but if an App or Package is set to High, then it&amp;rsquo;ll distribute regardless.
I wanted to see which apps and driver packages I had previously set to High priority for distribution and no longer need to be.
However, MECM doesn&amp;rsquo;t show this in any columns I could find. So I went to PowerShell.
Unfortuntely, the Get-CMApplications cmdlet doesn&amp;rsquo;t include any properties for &amp;lsquo;Priority&amp;rsquo; so, that was a bust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3rd Party Software Update failed, error 0x800703EE</title>
      <link>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2020/04/17/3rd-party-software-update-error-0x800703EE/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grantdickins.co.uk/2020/04/17/3rd-party-software-update-error-0x800703EE/</guid>
      <description>Recently when deploying 3rd Party Updates for Adobe Reader with Config Manager, I came across a bizarre error. After a quick search online, one post suggested deleting the \\machine\admin$\System32\GroupPolicy\Machine\Registry.pol
I don&amp;rsquo;t like deleting registry things, so it&amp;rsquo;s better to rename it.
But why? What has group policy got to do with Updates Deployments since Config Manager Client sets the Windows Update settings in Registry.
Lets look at the facts
The POL file date is 2 months old.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
